Preliminary Guide to the Richard Irvin & Co. Records circa 1824-1939 (bulk, 1860s-1919) MS 324
New-York Historical Society
- Series I. Files, circa 1843-1919
  - Contents of trunk 13 [marked "1888-1889"]
    - Insurance policies, miscellaneous, 1880s (Offsite-box 90)
    - Seconds of Exchange, 1886-1887, 1891 (Offsite-box 90)
    - Thirds of Exchange, 1882-1883 (Offsite-box 90)
    - Bills of Lading, outward, 1886-1889, 1891 (Offsite-box 90)
    - Drafts Paid, 1886-1890 (Offsite-box 90)
    - Stocks & Bonds Purchased & Sold, 1886-1888, 1891 (Offsite-box 90)
    - Sales, 1889-1890 (Offsite-box 90)
    - Statements of Exchange, 1891 (Offsite-box 90)
    - Adams Express Company receipt book, 1873-1890 (Offsite-box 91)
    - "Fire Insurance" account book, 1882-1891 (Offsite-box 91)
    - New York Mutual Insurance Company. Richard Irvin & Co. account book, 1883-1887 (Offsite-box 91)
    - Registered letter receipts, 1884-1890 (Offsite-box 91)
    - Mechanics' National Bank. Richard Irvin & Co. bankbooks, 1885-1886, 1888-1889 (Offsite-box 91)
    - Pneumatic Dynamite Gun Company receipts and vouchers, 1885-1888, 1890 (Offsite-box 91)
    - Acceptances, 1886 (Offsite-box 91)
    - Orders, 1886, 1888 (Offsite-box 91)
    - Bills, 1887-1889, 1891, 1894-1895 (Offsite-box 91)
    - Mechanics' National Bank checks, 1888, 1890-1891 (Offsite-box 91)
    - Miscellaneous bills, correspondence, receipts, etc., 1880s-1890s (Offsite-box 92)
  - Contents of trunk 14 [marked "1882-1883"]
    - Correspondence (bills), A-W, 1882 (Offsite-box 93)
    - Correspondence (bills), A-J, 1883 (Offsite-box 94)
    - Correspondence (bills), M-W, Y, 1883 (Offsite-box 94)
    - Thirds of Exchange, 1870, 1872 (Offsite-box 95)
    - "Package of papers taken out of tin box, November 14th, 1874" (Offsite-box 95)
    - Australian orders, 1882 (Offsite-box 95)
    - Purchases and sales. Notes, 1882 (Offsite-box 95)
    - Registered letter receipts, 1882 (Offsite-box 95)
    - R/A, 1882 (Offsite-box 95)
    - Guano. Storage(?) receipts, bills of lading, etc., 1882 or 1883 (Offsite-box 95)
    - Miscellaneous bills, 1882-1883 (Offsite-box 95)
    - Bills of lading, outward, 1883 (Offsite-box 95)
    - Old policies, fire insurance (expired 1883), before 1883 (Offsite-box 95)
    - National Trial Balance ledger, [1909?] (Offsite-box 95)
    - Miscellaneous loose and bundled documents, circa 1870s-1900? (Offsite-box 96)
  - Contents of trunk 15 [marked "City Glasgow Bank / R. & M. R.R."]
    - Western Union Railroad, correspondence, 1867 (Offsite-box 97)
    - Racine & Mississippi Rail Road, correspondence, 1860, 1863 (Offsite-box 97)
    - Racine & Mississippi Rail Road, weekly earnings and monthly statements, 1864 (Offsite-box 97)
    - Racine & Mississippi Rail Road, reports on law suits, etc., undated (Offsite-box 97)
    - City of Glasgow Bank, correspondence, 1857-1861, 1865-1866, 1872 (Offsite-box 97)
    - City of Glasgow Bank against William Mackinson, court documents and reports, 1881 (Offsite-box 98)
    - [New York University processing intern's list of Richard Irvin & Co. volumes in Series II, and "Letter to My Successor"], [1945] (Offsite-box 98)
      General
      A copy of the volume list is also kept at the Manuscript Reference desk.
- Series II. Bound volumes, circa 1848-1914
  Series II contains 394 bound volumes of a mostly financial and transactional nature, ranging from about 1848 through 1914, and, possibly, as early as 1824 and as late as 1939. The volumes include account books of various type (e.g., balances, bills payable, cash books, checkbooks, gold accounts, invoices, investments, ledgers, journals, sales, stocks and bonds, and ventures), letter books recording Richard Irvin & Co.'s voluminous commercial correspondence (bulk, 1865–1900), the occasional scrapbook of telegram and cable copies, and a handful of published books (such as Charles Ezra Sprague's Tables of Compound Interest, Discount, Annuities, Sinking Funds and Other Computations for use in the Accountancy of Investment).
  The container list provides an inventory of all volumes. However, when the inventory was taken, all volumes had been shrink-wrapped for off-site storage. Consequently, the inventory is not based on a review of the volume content, but was drawn from a list assembled by a New York University intern who surveyed the collection in 1945, as well as any labeling visible on the spines, inferences, and other observations short of unwrapping the volumes. Thus, many are thus entered as "contents unknown." Inaccuracies, especially in date ranges, are likely. The absence of a date range in the container list means that no dates were observed on the exterior of the shrink-wrapped volume.
  In 2019-2020, in preparing the bound volumes of the collection for off-site storage, each volume was given a sequence number (SN), which simply indicated the order of the volumes as found on the shelves. This finding aid presents the volumes in that same order, with reference to the sequence number. Related volumes were often found together on the shelves, but there was also a considerable degree of randomness that is reflected in the container list. Parenthetical numbers following some titles represent Richard Irvin & Co.'s in-house organizational scheme.
  - Trial Balance (Volume SN-1)
  - I R and G P I Co. (Volume SN-2)
  - American School of Opera. National Conservatory of Music (Volume SN-3)
  - Niagara (2) [Niagara Emery Mills, Inc.?] (Volume SN-4)
  - Niagara (6) [Niagara Emery Mills, Inc.?] (Volume SN-5)
  - Letter book (2). Order Book, 1868 June 4 - 1876 November 11 (Volume SN-6)
  - Letter book (3). Satterthwaite, 1873 October 3 - 1876 January 3 (Volume SN-7)
  - Letter book. Adamite Surface Machine Co. (Volume SN-8)
  - Letter book. M-B Motor Co. [Maxwell-Briscoe Motor Company] (1), 190[4] May 3 - 1906 April 19 (Volume SN-9)
  - Letter book. M-B Motor Co. [Maxwell-Briscoe Motor Company] (2), 1906 April 23 - 1907 October 30 (Volume SN-10)
  - Letter book. M-B Motor Co. [Maxwell-Briscoe Motor Company] (3), 1907 November 1 - 1908 October 2 (Volume SN-11)
  - Letter book. Automobile (1), 1906 October 18 - 1907 August 26 (Volume SN-12)
  - Letter book. Automobile (2) (Volume SN-13)
  - Maxwell Briscoe, Etc., 1910-1914 (Volume SN-14)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-15)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-16)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-17)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-18)
  - Muldoon Underwear Co. (Volume SN-19)
  - Muldoon Underwear Co. (Volume SN-20)
  - Sales No. 1 "J" (Volume SN-21)
  - Sales No. 2 "R" (Volume SN-22)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-23)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-24)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-25)
  - Letter book (58), 1865 [July?] - September (Volume SN-26)
  - Letter book (59), 1865 - 1866 March 16 (Volume SN-27)
  - Letter book (60), 1865 February 16 - 1866 May 29 (Volume SN-28)
  - Letter book (62), 1866 August 21 - November 7 (Volume SN-29)
  - Letter book (63), 1866 November 7 - 1867 February 2 (Volume SN-30)
  - Letter book (64), 1867 February 2 - May 28 (Volume SN-31)
  - Letter book (65), 1867 May 28 - August 26 (Volume SN-32)
  - Letter book (66), 1867 August 26 - December 11 (Volume SN-33)
  - Letter book (67), 1867 December 11 - 1868 April 7 (Volume SN-34)
  - Letter book (68), 1868 April 7 - July 25 (Volume SN-35)
  - Letter book (69), 1868 July 25 - October 30 (Volume SN-36)
  - Letter book (70), 1868 October - 1869 January 16 (Volume SN-37)
  - Letter book (71), 1869 January 16 - April 23 (Volume SN-38)
  - Letter book (72), 1869 April 23 - July 29 (Volume SN-39)
  - Letter book (73), 1869 July 29 - November 1 (Volume SN-40)
  - Letter book (75), 1870 February 9 - June 25 (Volume SN-41)
  - Letter book (76), 1870 June 25 - November 5 (Volume SN-42)
  - Letter book (77), 1870 November 5 - 1871 March 3 (Volume SN-43)
  - Letter book (78), 1871 March 3 - July 8 (Volume SN-44)
  - Letter book (79), 1871 July 8 - November 4 (Volume SN-45)
  - Letter book (80), 1871 November 4 - 1872 February 26 (Volume SN-46)
  - Letter book (81), 1872 February 26 - July 5 (Volume SN-47)
  - Letter book (82), 1872 July 5 - November 14 (Volume SN-48)
  - Letter book (83), 1872 November 14 - 1873 March 8 (Volume SN-49)
  - Letter book (86), 1873 December 19 - 1874 March 1 (Volume SN-50)
  - Letter book (92), 1876 August 24 - 1877 February 19 (Volume SN-51)
  - Letter book (97), 1879 October 7 - 1880 April 9 (Volume SN-52)
  - Letter book (98), 1880 April 24 - December 16 (Volume SN-53)
  - Letter book (99), 1880 December 16 - 1881 July (Volume SN-54)
  - Letter book (101) (Volume SN-55)
  - Letter book (102), 1882 November 9 - 1883 July 24 (Volume SN-56)
  - Letter book (103), 1883 July 24 - 1884 March 22 (Volume SN-57)
  - Letter book (106), 1885 July 10 - 1886 March 26 (Volume SN-58)
  - Letter book (107), 1886 March 26 - November 26 (Volume SN-59)
  - Letter book (109), 1887 June 17 - 1888 January 5 (Volume SN-60)
  - Letter book (111), 1888 August 8 - 1889 February 26 (Volume SN-61)
  - Letter book (112), 1889 February 27 - October 31 (Volume SN-62)
  - Letter book (113), 1889 October 31 - 1890 July 21 (Volume SN-63)
  - Letter book (114), 1890 July 21 - 1891 April 6 (Volume SN-64)
  - Letter book (115), 1891 April 6 - 1892 January 8 (Volume SN-65)
  - Letter book (117), 1892 January 4 - 1893 June 26 (Volume SN-66)
  - Letter book (118), 1893 June 26 - 1894 April [August?] 5 (Volume SN-67)
  - Letter book (119), 1894 April [August?] 6 - 1895 March 5 (Volume SN-68)
  - Letter book (122), 1898 September 19 - 1899 February 1 (Volume SN-69)
  - Letter book (124), 1899 February 1 [4?] - April 26 (Volume SN-70)
  - Letter book (125), 1899 April 26 - July 24 (Volume SN-71)
  - Letter book (126), 1899 July 24 - November 22 (Volume SN-72)
  - Letter book (127), 1899 November 22 - 1900 March 13 (Volume SN-73)
  - Letter book (128), 1900 March 13 - April 28 (Volume SN-74)
  - Letter book (129), 1900 April 28 - June 26 (Volume SN-75)
  - Letter book (130), 1900 June 25 - August 20 (Volume SN-76)
  - Letter book (132), 1900 October 31 - 1901 January 3 (Volume SN-77)
  - Letter book (133), 1901 January 3 - March 6 (Volume SN-78)
  - Letter book (134), 1901 March [6? 7?] - May 3 (Volume SN-79)
  - Letter book (135), 1901 May 3 - July 11 (Volume SN-80)
  - Letter book (136), 1901 July 11 - September 25 (Volume SN-81)
  - Letter book (137), 1901 September 25 - November 25 (Volume SN-82)
  - Letter book (142), 1901 November 1 - 1903 January 24 (Volume SN-83)
  - Letter book (146), 1903 November 12 - 1904 February 27 (Volume SN-84)
  - Letter book (147), 1904 February [26?] 27 - July 13 (Volume SN-85)
  - Letter book (148), 1904 July 13 - November 13 [19?] (Volume SN-86)
  - Letter book (149), 1904 November 14 - 1905 April 6 (Volume SN-87)
  - Letter book (150), 1905 April 6 - September [1?] 6 (Volume SN-88)
  - Letter book (151), 1905 September 6 - 1906 February 9 (Volume SN-89)
  - Letter book (152), 1906 February 9 - June 21 (Volume SN-90)
  - Letter book (153), 1906 June 21 - November 16 (Volume SN-91)
  - Letter book (154), 1906 November 19 - 1907 September 18 (Volume SN-92)
  - Letter book (156), 1908 August 13 - October 10 (Volume SN-93)
  - Letter book (157), 1911 October [28?] - 1912 February [26?] (Volume SN-94)
  - Letter book (159), 1912 August 16 - 1913 January 31 (Volume SN-95)
  - Letter book (162), 1914 February 2 - August [22?] (Volume SN-96)
  - Letter book (163), 1914 August 22 - [?] (Volume SN-97)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-98)
  - Melbourne Shipments, 1858-1867 (Volume SN-99)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-100)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-101)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-102)
  - City of Glasgow Bank (4) (Volume SN-103)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-104)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-105)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-106)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-107)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-108)
  - Index Correspondence, Customers &c, 1899 June 1 - 1900 October 13 (Volume SN-109)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-110)
  - [Journal?], 1900 (Volume SN-111)
  - Trial Balance (Volume SN-112)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-113)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-114)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-115)
  - Orders (2) (Volume SN-116)
  - Letter book (Volume SN-117)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-118)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-119)
  - Quotations "B", 1899 September 22 - 1900 May 1 (Volume SN-120)
  - Samuel Irvin Statements, 1881 January - 1885 December 2 (Volume SN-121)
  - Advice of Exchange Order Reports, 1900 October 8 - 1904 May 16 (Volume SN-122)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-123)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-124)
  - [Securities?], [1867 July 15 - ?] (Volume SN-125)
  - 1900 Census Rand, McNally & Co.'s Enlarged Business Atlas and Shipper's Guide, Containing Large Scale Maps of all States and Territories in the United States, The Dominion of Canada, The Republic of Mexico, Central America, The West Indies, Cuba, Puerto Rico, Hawaii, The Philippines and China showing in detail The Entire Railroad System, 1901 (Volume SN-126)
  - A.A. Grant. Grant's Bankers and Brokers Railroad Atlas, 1888 (Volume SN-127)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-128)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-129)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-130)
  - Inward Freight (Volume SN-131.1)
  - Fairchance Iron Company, also William Marshall's Account, 1872-1878 (Volume SN-131.2)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-132)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-133)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-134)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-135)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-136)
  - Bonds & Stocks, 1871 June - 1876 (Volume SN-137)
  - Bills of Lading Outward (Volume SN-138)
  - Suppliers Index (3 pages used) (Volume SN-139)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-140)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-141)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-142)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-143)
  - Invoices, 1901 July 17 - ? (Volume SN-144)
  - Cables and Telegrams (Volume SN-145)
  - Trial Balance, 1901 July - 1905 June (Volume SN-146)
  - Order book (Volume SN-147)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-148)
  - Journal (Volume SN-149)
  - [Journal?] (Volume SN-150)
  - Journal (Volume SN-151)
  - [Journal?] (Volume SN-152)
  - [Journal?] (Volume SN-153)
  - [Journal?] (Volume SN-154)
  - [Journal?] (Volume SN-155)
  - Journal (Volume SN-156)
  - [Journal?] (Volume SN-157)
  - [Journal?] (Volume SN-158)
  - Journal (Volume SN-159)
  - [Journal?] (Volume SN-160)
  - Journal (Volume SN-161)
  - [Ledg]er (Volume SN-162)
  - [Journ]al (Volume SN-163)
  - Ledger (Volume SN-164)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-165)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-166)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-167)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-168)
  - Journal (Volume SN-169)
  - Journal (Volume SN-170)
  - [Ledg]er (Volume SN-171)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-172)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-173)
  - Journal "Y" (Volume SN-174)
  - Journal "B" (2) (Volume SN-175)
  - Journal "V" (Volume SN-176)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-177)
  - Journal (Volume SN-178)
  - Journal (Volume SN-179)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-180)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-181)
  - Journal "C" (Volume SN-182)
  - [Jour]nal "R" (Volume SN-183)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-184)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-185)
  - Ledger (Volume SN-186)
  - Journal "D" (Volume SN-187)
  - Cash "E" (10) (Volume SN-188)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-189)
  - Journal (Volume SN-190)
  - [Journal?] "A" (2) (Volume SN-191)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-192)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-193)
  - Account Current "K" (Volume SN-194)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-195)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-196)
  - Cash "C" (Volume SN-197)
  - [Cas]h (Volume SN-198)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-199)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-200)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-201)
  - Account Current "J" (Volume SN-202)
  - Ledger (Volume SN-203)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-204)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-205)
  - [Invo]ices [In]ward? [Out]ward? ["F"] (Volume SN-206)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-207)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-208)
  - Accounts, 1886 (Volume SN-209)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-210)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-211)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-212)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-213)
  - Exchange Ledger (Volume SN-214)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-215)
  - [Journal?] (Volume SN-216)
  - Ledger (Volume SN-217)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-218)
  - Customers Requirements (Volume SN-219)
  - Catalogues & Circulars (2) (Volume SN-220)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-221)
  - [Inv]oices [In]ward? [Out]ward? (Volume SN-222)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-223)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-224)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-225)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-226)
  - Shipping Register Outward (Volume SN-227)
  - Record of Inquiries (1) (Volume SN-228)
  - Cash "F" (Volume SN-229)
  - Package Record (Volume SN-230)
  - Current Quotations of Staples (Volume SN-231)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-232)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-233)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-234)
  - [contents unknown], "L" (Volume SN-235)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-236)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-237)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-238)
  - Exchanges No. 17 (Volume SN-239)
  - Journal (Volume SN-240)
  - Cash "P", 1889 January - 1896 January (Volume SN-241)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-242)
  - Purchase Ledger (1) (Volume SN-243)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-244)
  - Cash "A" (Volume SN-245)
  - Journal "D" (Volume SN-246)
  - [contents unknown], 1902-1905 (Volume SN-247)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-248)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-249)
  - Invoices (2), 1900 September 21 - 1902 March 31 (Volume SN-250)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-251)
  - Purchase & Sales (Volume SN-252)
  - Purchase & Sales (Volume SN-253)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-254)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-255)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-256)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-257)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-258)
  - Invoices "L" (Volume SN-259)
  - Exchanges (19) (Volume SN-260)
  - Invoices "K", 1902 January - 1905 July (Volume SN-261)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-262)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-263)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-264)
  - Accounts, 1896 June 9 - 1900 October 1 (Volume SN-265)
  - Balances (Volume SN-266)
  - #121 (9), 1896 April 11 - ? (Volume SN-267)
  - Journal (Volume SN-268)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-269)
  - Journal (Volume SN-270)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-271)
  - Exchange Account, 186[?] (Volume SN-272)
  - Accounts. Gibbs Bright... (Volume SN-273)
  - Building Index Locations (Volume SN-274)
  - Cole Estate (Volume SN-275)
  - Bonds given at Custom House & Internal Revenue Office, 1863 May (Volume SN-276)
  - Scrap Book (Volume SN-277)
  - Mechanics' National Bank. Checks. John Bruce Estate (Volume SN-278)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-279)
  - Quotations from May to... (Volume SN-280)
  - [contents unknown], 1898 February 18 - 1899 May 18 (Volume SN-281)
  - Invoices, [1882?] February [21? 23?] - October [13?] (Volume SN-282)
  - [E]xpiry Register (Volume SN-283)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-284)
  - Orders (3), 1888 October 24 - 1896 April 6 (Volume SN-285)
  - John Bruce [& Alex Irvin?], [1874 December 4 - 1888 August 8?] (Volume SN-286)
  - [Letter book?] (95), [1878 May 15 - 1879 February 11?] (Volume SN-287)
  - IRVIN (Volume SN-288)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-289)
  - Letter book (4). Satterthwaite, 1876 January 28 - 1879 April (Volume SN-290)
  - Letter book. [Gibbs Bright?], [1872 April - 1876 February] (Volume SN-291)
  - Letter book (3) [sic]. Satterthwaite, [1873 October 3 - 1876 January 3?] (Volume SN-292)
  - Bright S C (3) (Volume SN-293)
  - Bright Bros. & Co. (2) (Volume SN-294)
  - Letter book (Volume SN-295)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-296)
  - Letter book (Volume SN-297)
  - Inquiry book, 1898 (Volume SN-298)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-299)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-300)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-301)
  - Letter book. San Francisco (1), 1900 March 12 - ? (Volume SN-302)
  - Letter book "N" (Volume SN-303)
  - Orders (2) (Volume SN-304)
  - Letter book. Export and Import, 1900 September 20 - 1901 January 8 (Volume SN-305)
  - Letter book. London Agency (1), 1898 July 12 - 1899 July 18 (Volume SN-306)
  - Letter book. London Agency (4), 1900 September 29 - 1901 March 29 (Volume SN-307)
  - Letter book. London [Agency] (6) (Volume SN-308)
  - [contents unknown] [Letter book. London Agency (3)? Telegraph copies?], 1900 April 25 - September 2 [21?] (Volume SN-309)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-310)
  - Ship Dip & Ointment, 1897 November 30 - 1899 June 23 (Volume SN-311)
  - Letter book (5). Satterthwaite, 1879 April 15 - 1881 May 28 (Volume SN-312)
  - Letter book (6). Satterthwaite, [1881 May 28 - 1883 September 1?] (Volume SN-313)
  - Letter book (7). Satterthwaite, 1883 September 1 - 1887 February 2 (Volume SN-314)
  - Letter book (8). Satterthwaite, 1887 March - 1890 June 3 (Volume SN-315)
  - Letter book. Samuel Irvin (Volume SN-316)
  - Letter book. Samuel Irvin (Volume SN-317)
  - Samuel Irvin Statements (Volume SN-318)
  - Letter book. Samuel Irvin (Volume SN-319)
  - Letter book. Export and Import, 1900 March 9 - September 19 (Volume SN-320)
  - Letter book. Mrs. Mary M. Irvin, 1898 January 1 [or 17?] - 1899 June 10 (Volume SN-321)
  - Letter book. Iron & Steel. Pneumatic Mattress and Cushion Company, 1900 March 23 - August 8 (Volume SN-322)
  - Orders (Volume SN-323)
  - Letter book. Gibbs (13). Liverpool, London and So. America (Volume SN-324)
  - Letter book. Gibbs Bright (4). Australia, 1880 August 2 [20?] - 1892 April [May?] 2 (Volume SN-325)
  - Letter book (61). General, 1866 May 29 - August 21 (Volume SN-326)
  - [Letter book?] (74). General, 1869 November 1 - 1870 February 9 (Volume SN-327)
  - Melbourne Orders (2), [1868 May 11 - 1881 May 11?] (Volume SN-328)
  - Annual report of the Forest Commission of the State of New York for 1885, 1886 (Volume SN-329)
  - Charles Ezra Sprague. Tables of Compound Interest, Discount, Annuities, Sinking Funds and Other Computations for use in the Accountancy of Investment, [circa 1908?] (Volume SN-330)
  - Checks, 1888 September 27 - ? (Volume SN-331)
  - Mechanics' National Bank. Checks (Volume SN-332)
  - Receivable (Volume SN-333)
  - Royal Insurance Co. (Volume SN-334)
  - North British & Mercantile Insurance Co. (1) (Volume SN-335)
  - Imperial Fire Insurance Co. (Volume SN-336)
  - National Fire Insurance Co. (Volume SN-337)
  - Fire Insurance with Guardian Assurance Company of London (Volume SN-338)
  - London Assurance Corporation, Ocean Marine Insurance Company. Gold (Volume SN-339)
  - New York Mutual Insurance Co. (Volume SN-340)
  - Imperial Fire Insurance Co. and Northern Assurance Co. (Volume SN-341)
  - United States Lloyd's. Gold (Volume SN-342)
  - New York Mutual Insurance Co. Gold (Volume SN-343)
  - [contents unknown], 1884-1886 (Volume SN-344)
  - Mechanics' National Bank. Checks (Volume SN-345)
  - First Glasgow Directory [reprint?], [1787] (Volume SN-346)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-347)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-348)
  - [contents unknown] (wrapped with SN-350) (Volume SN-349)
  - [contents unknown] (wrapped with SN-349) (Volume SN-350)
  - Pig Iron, 1879-1888 (Volume SN-351)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-352)
  - Mechanics' National Bank. Checks (Volume SN-353)
  - Mechanics' National Bank. Checks (Volume SN-354)
  - Fire Insurance (Volume SN-355)
  - Mechanics' National Bank. Checks (Volume SN-356)
  - Mechanics' National Bank. Checks (48) (Volume SN-357)
  - [contents unknown] (Volume SN-358)
  - Exchange Account (Volume SN-359)